Mizuho Okimoto

Toronto, Ontario, Canada Email: mizuho.tiho@gmail.com

WFRSITFS

React.js - Restaurant API

Developed a user-friendly web application to showcase local restaurants using React.js for the front-end and Node/Express for the back-end. Integrated MongoDB Atlas for robust data management and Leaflet for interactive map displays.

PROJECTS

This project was driven by a desire to enhance local restaurant visibility and user engagement. It challenged and improved my skills in full-stack development, API integration, and responsive design, resulting in a well-received and functional application.

Angular.js - Music Discography API

Created an engaging music discovery platform using Angular.js, integrating MongoDB for data management and Spotify's API for music content. Features include displaying artist and song information, song playback, and a favorites registration function. Additionally, I implemented a membership registration system to personalize the user experience.

This project enhanced my skills in API integration, user interface design, and building interactive web applications, catering to music enthusiasts' needs for exploring and enjoying new music.

Fragments Microservice

- Implement a production-ready microservice to demonstrate service-oriented architectures as a cloud design pattern (https://github.com/MizuhoOkimoto/fragments)
- Utilize Amazon Cognito, EC2, Elastic Container Service, S3, DynamoDB
- Containerize applications in order to simplify, standardize, and secure deployments across development, test, and production environments
- Implement JEST and Hurl for the unit and integration tests
- Employ CI and CD as a software development methodology

Open-Source Development

- Develop Static Site Generator (https://www.npmjs.com/package/pajama-ssg)
- Contributed to the modernization of the C language course notes used at Seneca College (https://intro2c.sdds.ca)

EDUCATION	
Computer Programming and Analysis Ontario College Advanced Diploma, Sep 2019 – Dec 2022 Seneca College - GPA: 3.9/4 with President's Honours	
OTHER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE	

Senior Server / Team Leader, Jan 2018 - Aug 2023 Kinton Ramen - Toronto ON

- Excelled in creating a personalized service to enhance each customer's dining experience, thereby fostering a loyal customer base.
- Problem-Solving & Initiative: Proactively identified and resolved customer service challenges.
- Larger responsibilities: training new servers, inventory checks, escalations, and quality control to ensure a consistent Kinton customer experience.

Sales and Human Resource Consultant, Mar 2013 - Sep 2017 Recruit Jobs Co., Ltd. - Japan

- Initiated and led on-site engagements with major clients, successfully increasing ad placements on media platforms by 44%.
- Implemented and integrated recruitment web pages and management systems, enabling data aggregation and analysis. Collaborated with partner companies to improve SEO and UI/UX, leading to annual contract renewals for the system and achieving the team's overall annual targets.
- As a consultant, contributed to clients' business plans and management challenges by assisting in the recruitment and development of talent, playing a key role in aiding clients' successful public listings.